what's up guys coach Bret contur here so
here's a video about how to strengthen
your grip for the deadlift and I want to
preface this by saying uh if you really
just if you had an indestructible spine
then you would just do a ton of
deadlifts you know a ton of extra double
overhand deadlifts a ton of heavy shrugs
and Farmers walks and things like that
that involve caring and and just holding
on to heavy stuff but all this stuff
loads up the spine and if you're
squatting and deadlifting a lot you may
like me you might find that it impairs
your deadlift training you know when I
was doing a ton of shrugs and Farmers
walks and trying to you know add in some
extra double overhead deadlift what I
found was my deadlift was not increasing
because I was beating my spine up from
all the grip work so I decided instead
to train my grip without loading up the
spine and uh and and my grip strengthen
just fine and ironically a lot of the
things I heard from people that no this
won't transfer the deadlift cuz it's a
different type of grip strengthening uh
Endeavor I found that it did transfer so
I don't believe a lot of the things you
say like that the grippers can't improve
deadlift strength but we'll get to that
later so the first tip I have is do
practice holding the the deadlift the
grip the lock out as long as you can on
your last rep of your last set of
deadlifts so you know but don't don't do
it early on in your dead Deft to work
out because it'll just fatigue your grip
for later on um so just on your last rep
just pull this for time hold it as long
as you can on your very last set cuz you
already did did you're not adding
deadlift volume into your workout you're
just holding that last
rep and that's something I see I saw
Constantine constantinos do back in the
day okay so that doesn't add compressive
load to your spine because once again
you're already going to do that anyway
that was your prescribed workout hold as
long as you can that's your specific
deadlift grip work and I just showed you
double overhead but I would do mix grip
um in in in uh you know in my regular
workouts so I should have shown you mix
grip um the next exercise is a
hang so you're going to just hang from a
bar and if you're really heavy like me I
can actually get a decent workout of
hanging with with with both hands but
what I do is I'll hold on to the side
and I'll do one arm hangs and then I'll
switch hands and then I'll go to double
so it looks like this I I can only do
like 10 seconds right now my grip isn't
that strong but I used to be able to get
25 seconds that's when my grip was its
alltime strongest so what I would do
here is hold on right here and just hang
from one arm like this one 2 3 four and
then do it for 10 seconds and then
switch do the other side hold it for
time time and you're just trying to use
this arm for balance and then you
optional after you do both arms then you
can just
hang double double arm like
this and I found that that works really
well cuz again it's no additional spinal
loading now the
next tip I have for you is to use these
grippers and these are so this would be
like for someone really weak or maybe a
female this
a spry made it spr I got this from them
but it's it's you can get a lot of reps
or they make weak grippers but these
grippers are from Iron Mine they're
captains of crush I only use the trainer
the T and the one there's people that
can close like a number four but I don't
even get into the two and three but I
found that these work really well I do
warm up with the trainer first and I
used to bust this out for like 50 reps
but then I got to I warmed up and then I
would do the one and I think I could
close this for like yeah it's hard to
just get a couple right now but I could
close this for like eight reps on each
side and uh you know what what matters
is just building up in strength um and
then the last tip I have for you is
called bench
squeezes and I learned
this from some of the strong men in my
gym it's funny cuz you wouldn't think of
strong men
would do this exercise CU it looks
cheesy but it works really well all you
do is you grip the bench and you can do
wider closer you can do thumb here or no
thumb I like to do no thumbs and then
you just um squeeze as hard as you can
for like 10 seconds so you go one 2 3
four five and crush it crush it for 10
seconds now as far as volume goes if
you're doing a lot of pulling work and
back work then your grip might already
be fatigued a little bit so I wouldn't
do that much I would just add in like
two or three sets at the end of my
workouts like two or three days a week
and what I found is I could pull I got
up to where I could pull 620 lbs and my
grip was just fine but um and then once
I do a lot of grip work I maintain it
for a while but every once in a while
few times a year I've got to do grip
work for like you know 4 weeks and then
I get it strong again but all these
things I showed you don't add extra
compressive loading onto the spine they
don't beat up your back so you can use
that for deadlifting and do these extra
grip strength and exercises that aren't
going to interfere with your regular
training they're just going to help but
don't do too much volume you don't need
to do a ton of these you don't need to
do like six sets of these things just
add in a few sets it's going to help a
lot and then you can have your grip not
be your weak length and you don't want
to be inhibited by your grip CU what
I've found is when you have a weak grip
when when you go to pole you don't have
the power out off the ground it's like
your your when your grip is weak you
can't pull explosively because your
brain knows you're probably going to
drop it so you don't have that explosion
you want your grip to be way stronger
than your deadlift to where you can pull
confident and rip it off the ground and
pull explosively okay give these four
techniques a try and hopefully it'll
boost your deadlift and boost your grip
strength thanks for watching